## Lu Dong

(716) 730-0429; Buffalo, NY ludong@buffalo.edu

#### Deep Learning/Computer Vision

GitHub: dongludeeplearning LinkedIn: lu-dong-71bbb0224

I'm currently pursuing my Ph.D. at SUNY Buffalo, US. My research focuses on Human Behavior Modeling, which combines Reinforcement Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning, and Mathematical Optimization to analyze human dynamics in videos, images, and audios. I'm also experienced with Data Crawling, Pattern Mining, Information Retrieval, Full-Stack Search Engine Projects. I am a self-motivated and passionate person, good at communication and cooperation.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. Program in Computer Science and Engineering (GPA3.83), State University of New York at Buffalo (UB), USA. 08/2021-Now Ph.D. Program in Computing and Information Sciences.(GPA4.0), Rochester Institute of Technology (RIT), USA. 08/2020-05/2021 Master Degree in Computer Science and Technology (15/120), Xi'an Jiaotong University (XJTU), CHINA. 08/2013-05/2016 Bachelor Degree in Computer Science and Technology (10/150), Northeast Electric Power University, CHINA 08/2007-05/2011

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### **Human Pose Estimation with Reinforcement Learning**

Position:Research Assistant, Advisor:Dr.Ifeoma Nwoqu

08/2022-Now

@UB, USA

In this project, I delved into multiple models on tough pose estimation. Severe self-occlusion and missing body parts set up barriers for computer vision to understand the inner logic of human pose. To improve understanding of tough pose, I proposed to introduce reinforcement learning and build a self-enhancing dual-loop learning framework. Good judgement is not achieved overnight but is obtained through trials, and this co-evolution can be learned under self-supervision. To optimize the framework, we utilized 3D pose estimation, physical constrain, Motion synthesis technique. Relevant experiments are still in progress. Open to discuss.

#### **Zero-Shot Text-to-Motion Synthesis**

Position:Research Assistant, Advisor:Dr.Ifeoma Nwoqu

02/2022-Now

@UB, USA

- In this project, I explored various motion generation models and focus on generation on open-set. To generate novel categories that are not seen during training, we proposed AtomVAE for zero-shot text-to-motion synthesis. The main idea is to decompose seen actions into a sets of atomic actions and re-generate new motions with CVAE through semantic relationships.
- Masked motion autoencoder, diversity and sparsity constrain, classification loss, and disentangling latent variables have been used to optimize the model. The proposed end-to-end model achieves promising zero-shot results on NTU94 and UESTC Datasets. Meanwhile, the evaluation results outperform the state-of-the-art model even on close-set by a large margin.

#### Reinforcement Sign Language Translation (SLT) Research

Position:Research Assistant, Advisor:Dr.Ifeoma Nwoqu

02/2021-Now

@UB+RIT, USA

- I delved into various deep learning frameworks for sign language video-to-text translation to facilitate communication with the hearing impaired community. During this research, I successfully extracted gesture, expression-related features from each video frame and used the Transformer-based framework to generate the text translation. Meanwhile, I analyzed evaluation metrics in the text translation quality area and looked into some limitations of automatic translation.
- After that, I proposed and implemented a creativity model that introduced the idea of reinforcement learning and used the feed-back of various indicators as the composite rewards to re-consider the selection of the word for translation, making the translation more fluent and in line with human understanding. My model surprisingly increases the BLEU score from 9.58 to 10.63.

### General Characteristics and Classification of Chinese Folk Songs with Machine Learning Position: Research Assistant, Advisor: Dr. Xinyu Yang.

09/2014-05/2016

@XJTU, CHINA

- To better explore the MEME (genetic factors) of Chinese folk songs and address the scarcity Database Challenge, I started this research from scratch by auditing piano lessons, contacting authorities, and collecting library materials. Eventually, I contributed 200+ MIDI folk songs for the Chinese folk songs(1000+) database.
- After continuous research, I proposed and implemented a model that includes pattern mining and improved multi-layer melody clustering to explore the most representative structures of folk songs. In addition, I proposed and implemented a synthetic feature model containing both global and local perspectives to improve classification performance. Experiments demonstrated the superiority of our model and I made a presentation at the SMC International Conference to showcase our achievements.

#### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

#### Information Retrieval Project -Covid19 & Vaccine Analysis Search Engine

09/2021-12/2021 @UB

• Using Python and Tweepy, I crawled 50,000 tweets data. The variety of data includes three languages, three countries, authorities, and the general public. The collection topics are related to covid and vaccines. I implemented the Google-like UI with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Ajax; Flask as server, deployed on AWS EC2 cloud. My Back-end analyzed the authorities' trend along with the COVID19, attitudes towards vaccines, and impacts on the public.

# Lu Dong

(716) 730-0429; Buffalo, NY ludong@buffalo.edu

#### Deep Learning/Computer Vision

### 09/2021-12/2021 @UB

GitHub: dongludeeplearning

LinkedIn: lu-dong-71bbb0224

#### Reinforcement Learning Project - Multi-Agent Collaborative Reinforcement Learning

• I developed a system integrating multiple classic RL algorithms, including Q-Learning, SARSA, DQN, DDQN, Actor-Critic, and Actor-Critic variants. Besides, This system can successfully solved the multi-agent cooperation task, eg, pass the intersection. I designed and implemented a dynamic reward mechanism to adjust travel routes intelligently. The experimental results show the superefficient of my design, which could double the convergence efficiency.

#### Computer Vision Project - Multiple Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs)

09/2020-12/2020 @RIT

• Using Pytorch, based on the Fashion-Mnist dataset, I implemented and compared various GANs, like Vanilla MSE GAN, Wasserstein GAN (WGAN), Least Square GAN to generate 10 classes of clothes, shoes, and bags. I also went deep into the Mode Collapse issue that generation is not uniform in GANs. To reduce this effect, I implemented the Unrolled GAN. In addition, I explored and implemented Conditional GAN to make the generation process more controllable and intelligent.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Research Internship
Oppo US Research Center

05/2022-08/2022

@Palo Alto, CA, US

• I was in charge of the Human Pose Estimation Research of the OPPO Health Lab Project. A big challenge of home fitness applications is the tough pose estimation that includes severe self-occlusion. After delved into the latest algorithms, I developed three pipelines for 3D pose estimation under different scenarios to solve the tough pose estimation issues. All achieved better performance by a large margin than the previous pipeline. Besides, I was also responsible for part of model optimization and model deployment. A patent work is in progress.

Senior Data Analyst 09/2016-04/2020

Shaanxi Haina Electronic Technology Co.,LTD,

@XI'An, CHINA

- I was in charge of the research and development of Information Systems, proposed design solutions, integrated front-end and back-end code logic, and database storage to ensure the system's smooth operation.
- I was also responsible for the development and improvement of the Recommendation system. Specifically, combine collaborative filtering, query, and tags to generate candidate sets. Then, using ML techniques for fine scoring generates top N recommendations and multiple data visualizations. My related work made a big jump in customer satisfaction, improved from 70% to 85%.

#### **PUBLICATION**

[1] J. LI, Lu DONG, J-H DING, X-Y YANG; Exploring the General Melodic Characteristics of XinTianYou Folk Songs [C], 12th Sound and Music Computing Conference, Maynooth, Ireland. 2015:393-399.

#### SKILLS AND OTHERS

	·
Technical Skills	Python, PyTorch, C#, Anaconda, Matlab, Mathematical Modeling, MySQL, Apache Solr, AWS_EC2, Flask,
	Django, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Ajax, LaTex, Complexity Anslysis.
Language	English(fluency), Chinese (native), French (entry)
Honors	"Excellent Graduate Student", "Excellent Undergraduate Student", "Best Employee Award",
	Academic Scholarships, National Fellowships.
Activities	Love Sports, Captain of Champion Women Basketball Team, Silver Metal for 100M Hurdle; Second Prize
	in College Debate Competition.